Portfolio GitHub in LinkedIn

82 Plymouth Avenue, Maplewood, NJ 07040 • mark@alienresident.net • 347 228 3696

Summarv

I am a User Experience Designer with over fifteen years in interactive media. My career spans the breadth of digital production, from production art to web design and front-end development. As a User Experience Designer, my in depth understanding of the design process allows me to meet user goals while balancing aesthetics and technical constraints.

UX/UI Skills

- · Usability Testing, User Interviews, and Personas
- Sketching, Storyboarding, and Paper Prototyping
- · Wireframing, Card Sorting, and High-fidelity Prototyping
- · Markup (HTML) and Styling (CSS)
- · Visual Design, Style Guides, and Style Tiles
- · Typography and Graphic Production

Technical Skills

- · Sketch, Photoshop, OmniGraffle, Illustrator, Principle, Flash
- . HTML, CSS, Sass & Compass, Javascript & jQuery, Grunt & Gulp
- · Git & SVN, PHP, MySQL, Drupal

Professional Experience

KBS (kirshenbaum bond senecal)

March 2015-present

Associate Director, User Experience

KBS (kirshenbaum bond senecal) November 2016-present

- · Create a modular design system, wireframes, user flows, and prototypes for the responsive redesign of the BMW USA website
- · Create a Sketch and InVision based workflow to streamline work between departments. Where wireframes created by UX designers, are visualized by UI designers, and then prepared for handoff to developers

Senior User Experience Designer

Spies & Assassins | KBS (kirshenbaum bond senecal) March 2015-November 2015

- · Create wireframes, user flows, and prototypes for the redesign of the My BMW website
- · Create wireframes and user flows for the 360° interactive Tour of Tomorrow showcasing the innovations of new BMW 7 Series
- · Create mockups for the interactive informational signage for Bank of Montreal at Toronto's Billy Bishop Airport

New York University

October 2008-March 2015

User Experience Specialist

Digital Communications Group, Information Technology Services August 2014-March 2015

- Create a new responsive user interface for Sakai, an Open Source Learning Management System
- Commit back the user experience work from NYU Classes to Sakai
- Design a new user interface for NYU's Email Direct a bulk email communication tool for NYU administrators

User Experience Designer

Academic Technology Services, Information Technology Services October 2011-August 2014

- Design a new user interface for NYU Classes the Learning Management System (LMS) based on extensive usability testing
- Create a 'Mobile First' prototype for our redesign of MediaCommons a digital network for professors and post-graduate students of film and media studies

Interactive Designer and Developer

Faculty Technology Services, Information Technology Services October 2008-October 2011

- Design and develop MediaCommons a digital network for professors and post-graduate students - using Drupal
- · Establish a distinctive look and feel for the MediaCommons network and it's project sites
- Design and develop book and photo viewing websites, and streaming audio and video for the NYU Libraries' special digital collections

Columbia University August 2001–September 2008

Senior Web Designer and Developer

Columbia University Digital Knowledge Ventures (a small 'digital agency' within Columbia University)

May 2005-September 2008

- · Create educational course content and departmental websites for Columbia University and affiliated non-profits
- · Design and develop websites using open source content management systems and static html

Web Designer and Developer

Columbia University Digital Knowledge Ventures August 2001-May 2005

- · Work with Columbia Faculty to design and develop interactive e-seminars and courses
- Design and develop interactive maps, audio slideshows, podcasts, and basic video production and post-production for streaming video and DVD

Scholastic

January 2000-May 2001

Web Designer

e-Scholastic

- · Design educational, commercial, and promotional websites for Scholastic
- Design daily site graphics, flash based interactive guizzes and educational activities

Education

1999-2007 Ph.D. Media & Communication, European Graduate School, Saas-Fee, Switzerland

1998-2001 Certificate in Film Production, The New School, New York, NY

1995-1996 M.Phil. Medieval History, Trinity College, Dublin University, Ireland

1991-1994 B.A. History and Philosophy, University College Dublin, Ireland

Additional Information

Teaching

The New School, Fall 2004–Spring 2008 Adjunct faculty member, *Media Studies*

· Courses: Foundations of Media Design and Digital Video Effects

Columbia University, Summer 2005–Summer 2008 Instructor, *High School Program*

· Course: Digital Filmmaking

Organizations

- Co-Founder: NYU UX Group & NYU Web Designers and Developers Group
- Co-Organizer: DrupalCamp NYC 9 & 10 NYC Drupal Users Group
- Member: IxDA NYC UXPA Gotham Sass Meetup NYC Drupal Users Group Agile Experience Design Meetup • Type Directors Club

Selected Presentations, Event Organization, and Trainings

Presentations

- Beyond Putting Lipstick on the Pig at EdUI 2014 30th September, 2014
- Sakai: Meet MORPHEUS at Open Apereo 2014 2nd June, 2014
- Rapid Protoyping Techniques at TorchTech: UX Networking Breakfast 23rd April, 2014
- Fixing Broken User Experience at NYU ITS All Hands Meeting 21st September, 2012
- MediaCommons 2.0 at Digital Library Federation Forum 5th May, 2009

Event Organization

- UX Networking Breakfast Co-Organizer TorchTech & NYU UX group 23rd April, 2014
- UX @ NYU Co-Organizer NYU UX group 14th November, 2013
- Usability @ NYU Co-Organizer NYU UX group 11th December, 2012
- DrupalCamp NYC 9 & 10 Co-Organizer & Designer NYC Drupal Users Group June & December 2011

Trainings

- Leading Creative Ideation with Christian Linsey & Jen Zhao, Cooper U May 2016
- Design Leadership with Teresa Brazen & Lane Halley, Cooper U August 2015
- Scaling User Interfaces with Amy Schade, Nielsen Norman Group August 2014
- UX Leadership with Kim Goodwin, Rosenfeld Media October 2012
- Do It Yourself Usability Testing with Steve Krug, Rosenfeld Media May 2012
- Sketching Interfaces with Jason Mesut & Sam Smith, Interaction 12 February 2012
- Mobile Prototyping Essentials with Rachel Hinman, Interaction 12 February 2012